<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Paco Coursey]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Paco Coursey]]></description>
        <link>https://paco.im</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://paco.im/og.png</url>
            <title>Paco Coursey</title>
            <link>https://paco.im</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 19:08:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://paco.im/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Write it down]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>My shitty superpower is solving difficult problems as I&#39;m falling asleep. Doesn&#39;t sound too bad, right? Here&#39;s the catch: I always convince myself I don&#39;t need to write the solution down.</p>
<p>It&#39;s 1:18 AM. I just figured it out. The answer is so simple, I can&#39;t believe it took me this long. Do I blind myself opening my phone to write it down? No, I can finally sleep now! There&#39;s no way I&#39;ll forget.</p>
<p>It&#39;s 8:32 AM. I can&#39;t believe I&#39;ve done this again.</p>
<hr>
<p>I have a new policy: <strong>write it down.</strong> Every single time. No matter if the idea comes to me in the shower, the middle of a dream, or in a conversation.</p>
<p>Most of my ideas are bad. But this way I&#39;ll never miss an opportunity.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://paco.im/write-it-down</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://paco.im/write-it-down</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paco Coursey]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On Gaming]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>A favorite quote from an old friend.</p>
<blockquote>

<p>I really admire that there are people of all ages that are able to get along, without awkwardness, without serious fighting, and share a common interest, whilst in completely different parts of the world.</p>
<p>I mean, isn&#39;t it just amazing that we all have a different background, a different upbringing, a different future, and yet we all united at this point in time to share an interest, as futile as it may seem, and be passionate about it?</p>
<p><strong>What a life!</strong></p>
<p>— Giles</p>
</blockquote>
]]></description>
            <link>https://paco.im/on-gaming</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://paco.im/on-gaming</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paco Coursey]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ideas]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="code">Code</h2>
<ul>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> GUI for plain JSON databases using lowdb (<code>dead</code> - Dead Easy Array Databases)</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> MDX implementation using marked, custom HTML tags, and [data] attributes</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Deploy DB as a static file and use ISSG</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> styled-system HOC for use with styled-jsx</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> spotlight-like password manager with good keybinds</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Music gathering site, combines all other services to centralize a playlist</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="blog">Blog</h2>
<ul>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> The scroll position effect on /blog</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Introduction to mechanical keyboards</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Write it down</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Improved Structure Procrastination</li>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Thoughts on gaming</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Instrinsic value and pursuit of popularity</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> A decent popover</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="figma">Figma</h2>
<ul>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Minimal redesigns of popular websites</li>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Logos</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://paco.im/ideas</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://paco.im/ideas</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paco Coursey]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Good Writers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Have you noticed that some people write extremely well? Take Aaron Swartz&#39; article <a href="http://www.aaronsw.com/weblog/dweck" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&quot;Believe you can change&quot;</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Carol Dweck was obsessed with failure.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What an <em>amazing</em> first sentence. I&#39;m immediately glued to this article. Who is Carol Dweck? What&#39;s wrong with her?</p>
<p>If I were writing that, I&#39;d start with the immediately boring:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Carol Dweck is a Professor of Psychology at Stanford, studying the behavior of children and how they deal with failure.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Because I have a lot of practice writing in this dull manner that meets school requirements. But I&#39;m already bored reading it.</p>
<p>I&#39;m learning to recognize good writing, and I&#39;m fascinated. We all use the same set of words, but some writers are so much better at using them.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://paco.im/good-writers</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://paco.im/good-writers</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paco Coursey]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creative Output]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>I am consistently unhappy with my creative output. My job title includes designer, but I&#39;m not good at designing something from scratch.</p>
<p>None of work I create matches up to the work of designers that I admire. At a minimum, I want to feel more comfortable designing work that meets my own minimum expectations of quality. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impostor_syndrome" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Impostor Syndrome</a> probably plays a big part (especially working with such talented colleagues!) but maybe I simply need practice.</p>
<p>Creativity is not my strong suit. I&#39;m logical. Building on past experience to improve future work is something I am good at. Creating something new is not. That&#39;s why it feels like everything I create is a remix of my past work, or the work of others.</p>
<p>Does this still count as <em>my</em> creative output, though? I&#39;d argue that anything new in design is just old stuff reworked in new ways. Buried in sarcasm, <a href="https://twitter.com/markdalgleish/status/1084256955961466881" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mark Dalgleish</a> explains that step in the design process:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you&#39;re a developer who finds design difficult, you&#39;re probably skipping the &quot;inspiration&quot; phase—which, in non-designer speak, roughly translates to &quot;look at other designs and rip off all the good ideas&quot;.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is a totally valid way to work. It&#39;s probably the most efficient. You&#39;re not the first person working on your problems, so use what other people have already discovered. But to what degree can we claim this work as our own?</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://paco.im/creative</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://paco.im/creative</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paco Coursey]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Persistent Custom App Icons]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>I created <a href="https://dusk.now.sh" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dusk</a> to make my dock look more visually harmonious. <a href="https://freemacsoft.net/liteicon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LiteIcon</a> does a great job of automating the icon changing process, but every time I opened Discord, the dock icon reverted back to default. Not cool.</p>
<p><img src="https://paco.im/blog/persistent-icons/dock-1.png" alt="Original Discord Icon in Dock"></p>
<p>It happens to other Electron applications (Hyper, VSCode) over time. Even Safari reverts back occasionally. It&#39;s frustratingly ugly. Let&#39;s fix it.</p>
<p>Find the application in Finder and right click to &quot;Show Package Contents&quot;.</p>
<p><img src="https://paco.im/blog/persistent-icons/show.png" alt="Show Package Contents on Discord.app"></p>
<p>Navigate to <code>Contents/Resources/</code>. Here, <code>electron.icns</code> is the culprit. Let&#39;s replace it with our custom icon.</p>
<p><img src="https://paco.im/blog/persistent-icons/icns.png" alt="electron.icns in Contents/Resources Folder"></p>
<p>We&#39;ll need to convert our custom <code>.png</code> icon from Dusk (or anywhere else) to an <code>.icns</code> file. MacOS ships with the command line tool <code>sips</code> to help with this.</p>
<p>Run the following from the command line, replacing ICON as needed.</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">sips -s format icns ICON.png --out ICON.icns</code></pre>
<p>Move your new <code>.icns</code> file into the previously opened <code>Resources/</code> folder. I like to save the old icon by renaming it, just in case I have to revert later. Rename your new file to match the old (in this case, <code>electron.icns</code>).</p>
<p><img src="https://paco.im/blog/persistent-icons/fixed-icns.png" alt="New electron.icns File"></p>
<p>Restart the app, and your custom application icon should persist!</p>
<p><img src="https://paco.im/blog/persistent-icons/dock-2.png" alt="Much better"></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://paco.im/persistent-icons</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://paco.im/persistent-icons</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paco Coursey]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Understanding package.json]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>I began my Computer Science degree with an intensive introduction course in C. We used makefiles to compile and run each of our assignments.</p>
<p>When I started learning modern web development in early 2018, I had no idea what Node.js or NPM was. My idea of building website involved writing HTML, CSS, and occasionally including a <code>script</code> tag. A year or so later, I&#39;m finally comfortable with modern techniques.</p>
<p>A major source of confusion for me was <code>package.json</code>. In short, <code>package.json</code> is a makefile for the JavaScript environment, with some caveats.</p>
<h3 id="package-scripts">Package Scripts</h3>
<p>Package managers like Yarn and NPM also serve as script runners for JavaScript projects. Unlike makefiles, scripts in <code>package.json</code> run in a special environment.</p>
<p>Packages in <code>node_modules</code> that define an executable will have that executable appended to the environment PATH before running any scripts. This can be confusing. Let&#39;s see an example:</p>
<pre><code class="language-json">&quot;devDependencies&quot;: {
  &quot;eslint&quot;: &quot;1.0.0&quot;
},
&quot;scripts&quot;: {
  &quot;lint&quot;: &quot;eslint .&quot;
}</code></pre>
<p>Running <code>yarn lint</code> will work correctly. However, just running <code>eslint .</code> from the command line will fail!<sup>1</sup> This was extremely confusing at first, did I have  ESLint installed or not?</p>
<p>The package script will work because Yarn recognizes that the ESLint dependency includes an executable, and appends it to the environment PATH when running any scripts.</p>
<p>This is a great advantage of the modular nature of the JavaScript ecosystem. You don&#39;t have to install any global scripts or clutter up your PATH to work with JavaScript projects, just <code>yarn install</code>.</p>
<hr>
<ol>
<li>Unless you have installed ESLint globally, which does add the executable to your PATH (<code>yarn global add eslint</code>)</li>
</ol>
]]></description>
            <link>https://paco.im/understanding-package-json</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://paco.im/understanding-package-json</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Paco Coursey]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>